const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following is used to measure pH?","answers":[{"option":"pH scale","bool":false},{"option":"pH color","bool":false},{"option":"pH electrode","bool":false},{"option":"pH detector","bool":false},{"option":"pH meter","bool":true}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following correctly describes the first seven ribs?","answers":[{"option":"True ribs","bool":true},{"option":"Floating ribs","bool":false},{"option":"False ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Typical ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Atypical ribs","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"During a tooth extraction procedure, a broken tooth accidentally fell into the respiratory passage. What is the most common site for the foreign body to dislodge?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchioles","bool":false},{"option":"Trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal bronchus","bool":false},{"option":"Left bronchus","bool":false},{"option":"Right bronchus","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following is the major component of surfactant?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrosides","bool":false},{"option":"Gangliosides","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphatidyl lecithin","bool":false},{"option":"Dipalmitoyl phosphatidylcholine","bool":true}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"What is the most common route carbon dioxide takes to be transported to the cells?","answers":[{"option":"In the form of carbaminohemoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"In the form of bicarbonate ions","bool":true},{"option":"By dissolving in plasma","bool":false},{"option":"By binding to plasma proteins","bool":false},{"option":"In the form of carboxy hemoglobin","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"The phrenic nerve is accompanied by which of the following arteries?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior epigastric artery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal thoracic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Pericardiophrenic artery","bool":true},{"option":"Superior epigastric artery","bool":false},{"option":"Musculophrenic artery","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A doctor performs a surgery at the superior border of the intercostal space, causing pain. Which structure is damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Intercostal vessels","bool":true},{"option":"Epigastric vein","bool":false},{"option":"Intercostal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Hemiazygous vein","bool":false},{"option":"Azygous vein","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"The central chemoreceptors are stimulated maximally by which of the following chemical substance?","answers":[{"option":"High concentration of bicarbonate ions","bool":false},{"option":"High concentration of CO₂","bool":false},{"option":"Low partial pressure of oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"High concentration of hydrogen ions","bool":true},{"option":"High pH in blood","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"The students of first year MBBS are given a slide of the respiratory system. It shows all the usual layers: mucosa, submucosa, cartilage/muscular layer, and adventitia. Which of the following components of the respiratory airway has the greatest relative amount of smooth muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Larynx","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchioles","bool":false},{"option":"Trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchi","bool":true}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Pleural effusion is checked on X-ray at which of the following levels?","answers":[{"option":"Costophrenic angle","bool":true},{"option":"Cardiophrenic angle","bool":false},{"option":"Sternal angle","bool":false},{"option":"Base of the lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Infrasternal angle","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which metabolic imbalance is seen in respiratory alkalosis?","answers":[{"option":"Na only","bool":false},{"option":"K only","bool":false},{"option":"Ca and K","bool":true},{"option":"Ca only","bool":false},{"option":"Ca and Na","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following is a characteristic feature of the twelfth rib?","answers":[{"option":"Costal groove","bool":false},{"option":"Neck of the rib","bool":false},{"option":"Single facet on head","bool":true},{"option":"Costal cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Angle of the rib","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Caseating granulomas are found in tuberculosis. This is an example of which type of hypersensitivity?","answers":[{"option":"Type 3","bool":false},{"option":"Type 4","bool":true},{"option":"Type 1 (delayed)","bool":false},{"option":"Type 2","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1 (immediate)","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following sets of ribs exhibits the bucket handle movement during inspiration?","answers":[{"option":"Ribs 7 to 10","bool":true},{"option":"Floating ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Ribs 1 to 9","bool":false},{"option":"Attached ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Ribs 1-2","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A surgeon, while performing surgery, ligated the thoracic duct. Which of the following lymph drainage is not affected by this ligation?","answers":[{"option":"Diaphragmatic nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Left parasternal nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Left brachiomediastinal trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Right intercostal nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Left jugular trunk","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Lungs are supplied by pulmonary and bronchial vessels. Which of the following blood vessels carries poorly oxygenated blood from the heart to the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchial veins","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchial arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary veins","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary arteries","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"The pump handle movement of the rib cage involves which of the following ribs?","answers":[{"option":"2 to 10","bool":false},{"option":"7 to 10","bool":false},{"option":"2 to 6","bool":true},{"option":"7 to 12","bool":false},{"option":"1 to 7","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"What is the term for the 8th to the 16th week of the respiratory system development stage?","answers":[{"option":"Terminal sac stage","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar stage","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudoglandular stage","bool":true},{"option":"Embryonic stage","bool":false},{"option":"Canalicular stage","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"During respiratory movements, ribs act as a lever. Which of the following is the fulcrum of this lever?","answers":[{"option":"The tubercle of rib","bool":false},{"option":"At the angle of the rib","bool":false},{"option":"At the head of the rib","bool":false},{"option":"Medial to the tubercle of rib","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral to the tubercle of rib","bool":true}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following muscles is not involved in forced inspiration?","answers":[{"option":"Erector spinae","bool":true},{"option":"Scalenus medius","bool":false},{"option":"Scalenus anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Latissimus dorsi","bool":false},{"option":"Serratus anterior","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following structures is involved in the formation of the central tendon of the diaphragm?","answers":[{"option":"Cervical somites","bool":false},{"option":"Mesentery of the esophagus","bool":false},{"option":"Pleuroperitoneal membranes","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic somites","bool":false},{"option":"Septum transversum","bool":true}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following statements regarding the pleura is correct?","answers":[{"option":"It has two layers tightly adherent to each other","bool":false},{"option":"It forms the pulmonary ligament","bool":true},{"option":"It is lined by respiratory epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"The sternal line of pleural reflection is similar on right and left sides","bool":false},{"option":"It is insensitive","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"The inferior vena cava passes through the diaphragm at which of the following spinal levels?","answers":[{"option":"T8","bool":true},{"option":"C7","bool":false},{"option":"L1","bool":false},{"option":"T12","bool":false},{"option":"T10","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following structures passes through the diaphragm with the esophagus?","answers":[{"option":"Phrenic nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Azygos vein","bool":false},{"option":"Right vagus nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Intercostal vessels and nerve run between which of the following thoracic intercostal muscles?","answers":[{"option":"Subcostal and transversus thoracic muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Internal and innermost intercostal muscles","bool":true},{"option":"External and internal intercostal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Innermost intercostal and transversus thoracic muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Innermost intercostal and subcostal muscles","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A 42-year-old woman presents to the outpatient department with complaints of pain in the medial side of the forearm and wasting of hand muscles. The consultant diagnoses a compression of the lower trunk of the brachial plexus. Which of the following causes compression of the lower trunk of the brachial plexus?","answers":[{"option":"Second rib fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical rib","bool":true},{"option":"Abdominal rib","bool":false},{"option":"First rib fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Extra vertebrae","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A 35-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of chest pain that was felt in the ribs. After examination and investigation, a diagnosis of pressure on the intercostal nerves was made which resulted in a spasm of intercostal muscles. Which of the following muscles is unaffected?","answers":[{"option":"Pectoralis major","bool":true},{"option":"Internal intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"Innermost intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"Subcostal","bool":false},{"option":"External intercostal","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following maintains the patency of the trachea?","answers":[{"option":"Surface tension of water","bool":false},{"option":"Surfactant","bool":false},{"option":"Air pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudostratified ciliated epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Cartilaginous rings","bool":true}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following thoracic joints is incorrectly paired with its classification?","answers":[{"option":"Second to seventh sternocostal joints ---> Synovial joints","bool":false},{"option":"Interchondral joints ---> Secondary cartilaginous joints","bool":true},{"option":"Costochondral joints ---> Primary cartilaginous joints","bool":false},{"option":"Xiphisternal joint ---> Primary cartilaginous joint","bool":false},{"option":"Manubriosternal joint ---> Secondary cartilaginous joint","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following parts of the parietal pleura is supplied by the phrenic nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Cervical part","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral pleura","bool":false},{"option":"Costal part","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragmatic pleura (peripheral part)","bool":false},{"option":"Mediastinal pleura","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A newborn baby was observed to have continuous coughing and choking. There was an excessive amount of mucous and saliva secretion in the infant's mouth. The infant showed considerable difficulty breathing. The physician was not able to pass a catheter through the esophagus into the stomach. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Tracheal stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Tracheal atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal atresia and tracheoesophageal fistula","bool":true},{"option":"Hyaline membrane disease","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenal atresia","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following limits the duration of inspiration and subsequently increases the inspiratory rate?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal respiratory group of neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Chemotaxic center","bool":false},{"option":"Apneustic center","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumotaxic center","bool":true},{"option":"Ventral respiratory group of neurons","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following has a significant direct stimulatory effect on central chemoreceptors?","answers":[{"option":"Increased pH of blood","bool":false},{"option":"Increased hydrogen ions in cerebrospinal fluid","bool":true},{"option":"Decreases oxygen partial pressure of blood","bool":false},{"option":"Increased carbon dioxide in cerebrospinal fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Increased carbon dioxide in blood","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Mountain climbers have found that when they ascend a mountain slowly, over a longer period of days rather than a period of hours, they breathe much more deeply and therefore can withstand far lower atmospheric oxygen concentrations than when they ascend rapidly. What is this phenomenon called?","answers":[{"option":"Modification","bool":false},{"option":"Acclimatization","bool":true},{"option":"Alteration","bool":false},{"option":"Accommodation","bool":false},{"option":"Familiarization","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following is the most powerful respiratory stimulus for breathing in healthy individuals?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of oxygen in tissue","bool":false},{"option":"High pH and high carbon dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in pH of blood","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in pH of blood","bool":false},{"option":"Increased carbon dioxide in blood","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A patient presents to the emergency room with rib fractures. His breathing is painful so he is taking rapid, and shallow breaths. His respiratory rate is 40 breaths per minute and his tidal volume is 200 ml. What would be his minute respiratory volume?","answers":[{"option":"4600 ml/minute","bool":false},{"option":"2000 ml/minute","bool":false},{"option":"400 ml/minute","bool":false},{"option":"200 ml/minute","bool":false},{"option":"8000 ml/minute","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A 32-year-old man presents to the emergency room with a complaint of having trouble breathing after he met a road traffic accident. His lung function test shows his functional residual capacity to be reduced. What does this capacity indicate?","answers":[{"option":"The amount of air remaining in the lungs after normal expiration","bool":true},{"option":"The amount of air remaining in the lungs after maximum expiration","bool":false},{"option":"Combination of inspiratory reserve volume and tidal volume","bool":false},{"option":"The amount of air expelled out after each normal expiration","bool":false},{"option":"The amount of air inspired and expired during each normal breath","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following pressure differences is responsible for distention of the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"Airway opening pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Transpulmonary pressure","bool":true},{"option":"Transthoracic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Airway closing pressure","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Gases such as oxygen and carbon dioxide cross the respiratory membrane by which of the following methods?","answers":[{"option":"Passive diffusion through the lipid bilayer","bool":true},{"option":"Facilitated diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary active transport","bool":false},{"option":"Specific gas transport proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Primary active transport","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following events occurs in the lungs, when the partial pressure of oxygen falls below 73 mmHg in the alveolar air?","answers":[{"option":"Damage to type I pneumocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased physiological shunt","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in nitrogen content","bool":false},{"option":"Expansion of alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Constriction of blood vessel adjacent to alveoli","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A 24-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with complaints of a runny nose; red, itchy, and watery eyes; sneezing, and cough related to post-nasal drip. A diagnosis of allergic rhinitis is made. Which of the following chemical mediators is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Ranitidine","bool":false},{"option":"Histamine","bool":true},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"Diphenhydramine","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A person admitted to the hospital is in a coma. Analysis of arterial blood gave the following values: pCO₂ 56 mmHg, HCO₃ 25 mmol/l, and pH 7.1. What is the underlying acid-base disorder?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary edema","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":true}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A 4-year-old boy presents to the emergency room with complaints of malaise, lethargy, tachypnea, sore throat, abdominal pain, vomiting, and dehydration for the past week. He was known to have type I diabetes mellitus. His vitals showed a heart rate of 156 beats per minute, blood pressure of 90/55 mmHg, plasma glucose of 428.4 mg/dL, pH 6.7, pO₂ 5.2kPa, pCO₂ 4.4 kPa. The patient is diagnosed with Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). Dipalmityl phosphatidylcholine is the main constituent of pulmonary surfactants, 45% of which comes from de novo biosynthesis. Which of the following molecules give rise to the de novo synthesis of phosphatidylcholine in the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"Cytidine diacylglycerol","bool":false},{"option":"Cytidine triphosphate choline","bool":false},{"option":"Cytidine diphosphate choline","bool":true},{"option":"Cytidine phosphate choline","bool":false},{"option":"Lysophosphatidylcholine","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A person admitted to the hospital is in a coma. Analysis of arterial blood gave the following values: pCO₂ 16.1 mmHg, HCO₃ 5 mmol/l, and pH 7.1. What is the underlying acid-base disorder?","answers":[{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis with partial compensation","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following is the least likely characteristic of asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Airway hyperresponsiveness","bool":false},{"option":"Increased IgG immunoglobulins","bool":true},{"option":"Mast cell activation and degranulation","bool":false},{"option":"Increased mucus production","bool":false},{"option":"Infiltration of eosinophils into the airways","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Why do patients with emphysema often exhibit pursed-lip breathing?","answers":[{"option":"To prevent cyanosis and hypoperfusion","bool":false},{"option":"To regulate filling of lungs that have increased compliance","bool":false},{"option":"To avoid chest discomfort during inspiration","bool":false},{"option":"To increase airway pressure during expiration to reduce air trapping","bool":true},{"option":"Reflex response to severe breathlessness","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following is the most common congenital disease affecting the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"Lack of pulmonary surfactant protein B","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Tracheoesophageal fistula","bool":false},{"option":"Marfan syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital diaphragmatic hernia","bool":true}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following statements is most appropriate about lung diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Restrictive lung diseases are characterized by reduced expiratory flow rate","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive lung diseases are characterized by limitation to airflow","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive lung diseases are characterized by limitation to airflow","bool":true},{"option":"Restrictive lung diseases have partial obstruction at the level of bronchi","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive lung diseases are characterized by reduced expansion of lungs","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Concerning community-acquired pneumonia which of the following statements is the most appropriate?","answers":[{"option":"The incidence is 5-11 cases per 10,000 population","bool":false},{"option":"The most frequently identified organisms are gram negative bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Symptoms always include pleurisy","bool":false},{"option":"Risk factors include age (<5, >65 years)","bool":true},{"option":"Symptoms always include hemoptysis","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A 75-year-old man, hospitalized for the past week with COVID-19 pneumonia, develops a sudden onset of tachypnea and dyspnea. His lips appear blue and his oxygen saturation drops drastically. Chest X-Ray shows diffuse bilateral infiltrates (\"white lungs\"). What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute respiratory distress syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Miliary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Septicemia","bool":false},{"option":"Fat embolism","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A 59-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of frequent episodes of shortness of breath along with occasional cough with minimum sputum production for the last four years. He has been a known smoker for ten years. On chest auscultation, respiratory wheezes are heard. Chest X-Ray shows hyperinflation of both lungs. Pulmonary function tests show a decreased FEV₁/FVC ratio. Which of the following conditions is most likely to be a cause of these findings?","answers":[{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic pulmonary embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":true},{"option":"Diffuse alveolar damage","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive lung disease","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following is the most helpful and preferred method of establishing the diagnosis of asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Arterial blood gases","bool":false},{"option":"Chest X-Ray","bool":false},{"option":"Pulse oximeter","bool":false},{"option":"Chest computerized tomography (CT) scan","bool":false},{"option":"Spirometry","bool":true}]},{"id":52,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following is the single most effective test used in the DOTS strategy for the diagnosis of infective tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Chest X-Ray","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculin test","bool":false},{"option":"Sputum AFB smear microscopy","bool":true},{"option":"Gene Xpert test","bool":false},{"option":"Sputum for alpha fetoprotein (AFP) culture","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A 30-year-old woman is admitted to the medical ward with a complaint of acute exacerbation of bronchial asthma- a disease that she has been suffering from for six years. She has been advised of certain pulmonary function tests. Which of the following results are expected?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary function tests are not indicated","bool":false},{"option":"FEV₁/FVC ratio is increased","bool":false},{"option":"FEV₁/FVC ratio is reduced","bool":true},{"option":"FEV₁/FVC ratio is normal","bool":false},{"option":"FEV₁ will be increased","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A 4-year-old boy was brought to the outpatient department with complaints of nasal blockage and purulent discharge from the nose for four days. He is suspected to have inhaled a foreign body in the right main bronchus. Which anatomic feature of the right main bronchus favors the entry of a foreign body into it rather than the left main bronchus?","answers":[{"option":"Right main bronchus passes anterior to esophagus","bool":false},{"option":"Right main bronchus is more aligned with the trachea","bool":true},{"option":"Right main bronchus is longer","bool":false},{"option":"Right main bronchus is narrower","bool":false},{"option":"Right main bronchus is horizontal","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A 40-year-old woman presents to the outpatient department with complaints of chronic cough, shortness of breath, and cyanosis. She is diagnosed with restrictive lung disease on a pulmonary function test. Which of the following findings of the pulmonary function test suggest the diagnosis of restrictive lung disease?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased FEV₁","bool":false},{"option":"FEV₁/FVC ratio is increased","bool":true},{"option":"Increased FVC","bool":false},{"option":"No change in FEV₁/FVC ratio","bool":false},{"option":"FEV₁/FVC ratio is reduced","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"During a session of pleural effusion drainage, the physician asked the trainee to keep the needle just above the upper border of the lower rib. This was done to avoid injury to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Long thoracic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Intercostal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Neurovascular bundle","bool":false},{"option":"Intercostal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Intercostal artery","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which ions move outside of the red blood cells in the chloride shift?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium ions","bool":false},{"option":"Chloride ions","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium ions","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium ions","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrogen carbonate ions","bool":true}]},{"id":58,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following parts of the respiratory tract has the maximum number of smooth muscles?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchi","bool":false},{"option":"Alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiole","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory bronchiole","bool":false},{"option":"Trachea","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"The lungs receive arterial blood supply from two sources: the pulmonary arteries and the bronchial arteries. From which of the following does the right bronchial artery originate?","answers":[{"option":"Third posterior intercostal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior surface of the thoracic aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Second intercostal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior surface of the thoracic aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Upper left bronchial artery","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A patient comes to the emergency department with a low-pitched, hoarse voice, and noisy breathing. On examination, left vocal cords are found to be affected. Damage to which nerve can result in these findings?","answers":[{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Internal laryngeal","bool":false},{"option":"Left recurrent laryngeal","bool":true},{"option":"Intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"External laryngeal","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A 12-year-old girl presents to the emergency department with chest pain and labored breathing after falling off her bicycle. A chest x-ray reveals a fracture of the first rib. Which one of the following arteries is associated with the affected rib?","answers":[{"option":"Internal thoracic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Intercostal arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Perforating arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Subclavian artery","bool":true}]},{"id":62,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following pressures corresponds to the elastic forces which tend to collapse the lung?","answers":[{"option":"Pleural","bool":false},{"option":"Transpulmonary","bool":true},{"option":"Lung","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar","bool":false},{"option":"Transthoracic","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"An organ that is present in children and regresses by puberty is a constituent of which of the following mediastinum?","answers":[{"option":"Middle","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior","bool":false},{"option":"Superior","bool":true}]},{"id":64,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Trachealis is a band of muscle that exists between the open ends of the tracheal cartilages. What is its type?","answers":[{"option":"Hyaline","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth","bool":true},{"option":"Skeletal and smooth","bool":false},{"option":"Skeletal","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which respiratory organ has both skeletal muscles and cartilage?","answers":[{"option":"Trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal bronchiole","bool":false},{"option":"Larynx","bool":true},{"option":"Alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory bronchiole","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"In which of the following conditions is a barrel-shaped chest observed on examination?","answers":[{"option":"Lung cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"Which of the following corresponds to the total lung compliance of both lungs?","answers":[{"option":"300 ml of air/cm H₂O","bool":false},{"option":"250 ml of air/cm H₂O","bool":false},{"option":"400 ml of air/cm H₂O","bool":false},{"option":"100 ml of air/cm H₂O","bool":false},{"option":"200 ml of air/cm H₂O","bool":true}]},{"id":68,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"A child has difficulty breathing upon inhalation of pet dander dust and smoke. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Lung cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Nonatopic asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Atopic asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2022","question":"An 81-year-old patient is repetitively hospitalized due to respiratory tract infections. What of the following is the best advice that a doctor can give him to avoid future respiratory tract infections?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumococcal and influenza vaccine","bool":true},{"option":"Washing hands and maintain hygiene","bool":false},{"option":"Adenovirus vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus influenza B vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Proper diet","bool":false}]}]
export default arr